# Tyler J. Roberts

(262) 388-4050 | tjroberts314@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyleroberts | https://github.com/tyler314

# Summary

Software engineer with 6+ years experience in development and design. My most recent work has been well-balanced between building back-end systems, and front-end web applications. I'm seeking a role where I can leverage the experience I have to be a contributing member to a passionate team, that also requires me to learn new skill sets to succeed.

# Experience

# Software Engineer & Project Manager

Copper + Honey Salon  $\cdot$  Freelance

Feb 2023 - Present · Remote

- https://www.copperandhoneysalon.com
- Designed fully functional website from scratch, using AWS tools to quickly launch in time for the client's grand opening.
- Leveraged SEO techniques resulting in the website rising to the top Google Search results for hair extensions in the local area. Consistently receiving 300+ clicks/month.
- Designed solution for my clients to easily edit their employee info on their site at any time, seamlessly working across all screen sizes.
- Work directly with the owners and an independent UX Designer, in order to design software solutions, create timelines, and conduct demos.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Javascript, React. js, Material UI, SEO.

## Software Engineer

#### Warner Bros. Discovery · Contract

 $Mar 2023 - Dec 2023 \cdot Remote$ 

- Became key team contributor within first month by quickly becoming a part of on-call rotations, contributing to code reviews, and pushing code, allowing our team to meet the MAX launch deadline in May.
- Led efforts of designing novel integration tests, and setting up new Grafana monitoring + alerts for the team's new MAX services, in order to meet company SLA requirements.
- Lead engineer tasked with onboarding a new service from a re-org. Required collaboration with three away teams, to understand the service and get it running before my contract's end.
- General Operational Excellence. Conducted load tests before big launches, contributed to documentation for the new services we were building, etc.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Typescript, Node.js, Express.js, Kafka, Grafana, Kubernetes + Docker

# Software Engineer

#### Amazon.com · Full-Time

Dec 2019 — Jan 2023 · Seattle, WA

- Designed adapted responses for Smart Home requests. Features such as sharing customer insights, listing device capabilities, and a "Good Morning / Night" experience.
- Delivered Brief / Verbose Mode for ACMS. Developed filtering logic to serve personalized responses based on the individual customer's device setting.
- Migrated all Alexa personality content from a legacy CMS, to ACMS/ARMS. Three month endeavor that required the development of bulk migration scripts, working closely with a select few engineers, PMs, and content creators across all supported locales.
- Led the org in hiring engineers by conducting over 50 interviews in Q1 2022, resulting in a higher head count for hiring. Received the quarterly award for this effort.
- Social chair for the org, responsible for organizing quarterly events during the pandemic remote period, encouraging teammates to socialize and get to know each other better.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Kotlin, Javascript, React.js, CI/CD Code Pipelines, Git

## Software Engineer

#### Cockroach Labs · Full-Time

May 2019 − Sep 2019 · New York, NY

#### Cockroach Labs

- Apart of the Bulk I/O team, which is responsible for bulk operations in the database, including backup and restore, and schema changes in the database.
- Fixed issue where the dump operation would include interleaved table statements inside of create table statements, causing dependency issues upon a restore.
- Designed features for the backup & restore process to include additional metadata about the cluster. Required a redesign of how the process worked, and reduced manual steps by the user.
- Tools & Technologies: Golang, SQL, Git/Github.

# Software Engineer

#### Dataminr · Full-Time

Sep 2018 – Feb 2019 · New York, NY

- Work on developing the tools used to search and filter through the Twitter pipeline and other media sources.
- JVM code base comprised of Scala and Java. Applications ran on AWS, and much of the day to day work involved use with the AWS tech stack. Kinesis was used for processing the large data sources, where S3 was used to store the raw data.
- Migrated Pastebin data source from Kinesis to Kafka. Involved dependencies between several teams, and required collaboration amongst them.
- Tools & Technologies: Scala, Java, Maven, Docker, AWS, Google Guice, Git/Gitlab, IntelliJ, MacOS.

## Software Engineer

#### IBM Corporation · Full-Time

Jul 2017 – Aug 2019 · Yorktown Heights, NY

- Developed Python application on another team that moved their locally stored data and user accounts to Bluemix, IBM's cloud platform as a service.
- Designed and engineered a web application from the ground up using HTML, CSS, Angular, and Bootstrap. Responsible for the front-end, including page navigation using an MVC design pattern.
- Used Docker to rigorously test the deployment of the web application onto the servers.
- Tools & Technologies: Python, Docker, HTML, Angular, Javascript, PyCharm, MacOS.

# Education

B.S. Computer Engineering, Computer Science, & Mathematics with Physics Certificate (minor). University of Wisconsin - Madison, May 2017